# **MONY SARY**

La Cañada Flintridge, CA

Phone: (562) 607-9358 | Email: sary.mony@gmail.com LinkedIn: https://www.linkedin.com/in/mony-sary-08980b1aa/

> **GitHub**: <u>https://github.com/monysary</u> **Portfolio**: <u>https://www.monysary.com</u>

#### SUMMARY

Experienced full-stack web developer with a passion for developing innovative and user-friendly software solutions. Six years of work experience in research and development, project management, data analysis, and troubleshooting with confidence to meet the demands of a fast-paced tech environment. Self-starter with a calm demeanor, good work ethics, and the ability to independently and quickly learn new concepts while being proactive and maintaining deadlines.

# TECHNICAL SKILLS

Frontend: HTML, CSS, Javascript, jQuery, Bootstrap CSS, Tailwind CSS, Handlebars,

React, Material UI

Backend: Node, Express, APIs, Jest, Bcrypt, Socket.io, Git

Database: MySQL, Sequelize, MongoDB, Mongoose ODM, GraphQL, Apollo GraphQL

#### **P**ROJECTS

Name: Vacayte Travel App

**GitHub:** <a href="https://github.com/monysary/vacayte-travel-app">https://github.com/monysary/vacayte-travel-app</a>

**Link:** https://obscure-fjord-08413.herokuapp.com/

- Description: Vacayte is a travel app designed for adventurers to quickly and easily create their vacation itinerary by leveraging off of Yelp's API.
- Responsibilities: Created the entire front end and back end of the web app.
- Tools: React, Material UI, Node, Third Party API, Apollo GraphQL, MongoDB

Name: Pet Pals

**GitHub:** <a href="https://github.com/BryantTrinh/Pet-Pals-A-Social-Media-App-for-Pets">https://github.com/BryantTrinh/Pet-Pals-A-Social-Media-App-for-Pets</a>

**Link:** https://hidden-headland-00556.herokuapp.com/

- Description: Social media platform for pet owners to connect and chat with each other about their pets and schedule play dates.
- Responsibilities: Frontend coding of home, feed, and chatbox components.
   Backend coding of instant messaging feature with messages saving into database.
- Tools: React, Material UI, Node, Apollo GraphQL, MongoDB, Socket.io

Name: Breath of the Wild Encyclopedia

**GitHub:** <a href="https://github.com/monysary/Breath-of-the-Wild-Encyclopedia/">https://github.com/monysary/Breath-of-the-Wild-Encyclopedia/</a> **Link:** <a href="https://monysary.github.io/Breath-of-the-Wild-Encyclopedia/">https://monysary.github.io/Breath-of-the-Wild-Encyclopedia/</a>

- Description: A Legend of Zelda: Breath of the Wild encyclopedia made in the style
  of the games in-game item menu. Users can click and view in-game material to
  learn more about each item.
- Responsibilities: Created the user interface with mobile responsiveness. Created the API call and organized data to be presentable with the user interface.
- Tools: React, Material UI, Web API

#### EXPERIENCE

# Pangea Laboratory - Tustin, CA

2020 - Present

#### **Independent Contracting Consultant** - Oct 2022 to Present

- Review and edit proprietary documents pertaining to operations, quality assurance, standard procedure, and safety.
- Providing technical consultation for DNA sequencing tests and laboratory operations.

## Laboratory Manager - Jul 2020 to Oct 2022

- Managed two separate teams concurrently, all consisting of a total of 8 technicians, 2 Clinical Laboratory Scientists, and 1 Associate Scientist.
- Read regulatory documents and implement quality assurance standards in the lab.
- Analyzed laboratory operation to find deficiencies and corrected them in time for regulatory inspection.
- Wrote code using vendor's proprietary software to create methods performed by automated liquid handling robots.
- Researched solutions to improve laboratory operation speed and quality.
- Worked in a team of 10 to build an entire COVID-19 testing department within a matter of weeks.

# **Zymo Research Corp** - Irvine, CA

2018 - 2020

# Senior Research Associate - Jan 2020 to Jul 2020

- Trained and managed 2 laboratory associates to perform a DNA sequencing assay.
- Created a small scale Laboratory Information Management System using Excel and Macros for the sequencing assay.
- Identity and troubleshooted issues regarding the sequencing assay and high complexity instruments.
- Communicate with customers to provide solutions to issues with company products.

### Research Associate - Jun 2018 to Jan 2020

- Performed research and experiments on new materials for operations, and deployed its use in production.
- Sequenced 1000+ DNA samples with minimal mistakes and supervision, while maintaining the turnaround time.
- Provided technical support to customers through email and phone calls regarding general and technical company questions.

#### **EDUCATION**

Boot Camp Certificate: University of California Irvine, Irvine, CA

Feb 2023

A 12-week intensive program (24 CE units) focused on gaining technical programming skills in HTML, CSS, Javascript, jQuery, Bootstrap CSS, Node, MySQL, MongoDB, Express, Handlebars, and React.

Biological Sciences, B.S: University of California Irvine, Irvine, CA

Jun 2016